<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="assets/css/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://www.brianbaldock.com/">
  <title>Brian Baldock</title>
  <subtitle>This blog will have numerous amounts of subject matter that I think about and try to master</subtitle>
  <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/" />
  
  <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Brian Baldock</name>
    <email>bbaldock04@hotmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Opossum Symposium</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/" />
    <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;After what feels like an eternity without attending any conferences, today was a refreshing change. Thanks to Mr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://zachleat.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Zach Leatherman&lt;/a&gt; and his team, a virtual symposium for 11ty was brought to life, and I couldn’t have been happier to be a part of it. The lineup boasted familiar faces from Mastodon, whom I’ve followed for years, alongside many new names, all sharing insights into the world of web technologies. It was a joy to dive into their websites and Mastodon accounts, connecting with this vibrant community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mikeneumegen.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mike Neumegen&lt;/a&gt; for his stellar job as MC, and a big shoutout to Diane and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://whitecoatcaptioning.com/captioning-for-conferences/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;White Coat team for providing live captions&lt;/a&gt; throughout the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;kickoff&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/#kickoff&quot;&gt;Kickoff!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zach’s opening remarks set the perfect tone for the day. His humility in acknowledging the attendees and their enthusiastic participation in the chat was heartwarming. The love for the community was palpable, and it’s all thanks to Zach and his dedicated team. I’m eagerly anticipating version 3.0 and all the exciting developments they’ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/#speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each speaker brought a unique perspective to the table, sharing their insights and passions with authenticity. It was a refreshing experience to soak in their knowledge and emotions, with no hidden agendas or endorsements in sight. Just genuine stories and a shared enthusiasm for creativity, exploration, and the evolving landscape of design and web technologies. It left me inspired to continue my journey of creation and delve deeper into the fundamentals, guided by the spirit of curiosity and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Working Away</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/working-away/" />
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/working-away/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on my career journey thus far, I find myself chipping away at summarizing the noteworthy projects I’ve undertaken. It’s been a humbling exercise, delving into memories of the various milestones and discoveries along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having built numerous websites throughout my career, ranging from brochure-style sites to intricate portals, I’ve found immense satisfaction in the process. However, the real excitement comes when I get the opportunity to work on web applications. This allows me to delve deeper into backend technologies, gaining a comprehensive understanding of the layers of security, engineering, and design that operate behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each project has been a learning experience, allowing me to expand my skill set and refine my craft. From navigating the intricacies of frontend development to mastering the complexities of backend systems, I’ve embraced every challenge with enthusiasm and determination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to evolve in my career, I’m grateful for the opportunity to contribute to meaningful projects and make a tangible impact in the digital landscape. With each new endeavor, I look forward to further growth, exploration, and discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Site</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/new-site/" />
    <updated>2024-03-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/new-site/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been awhile since I dedicated time to working on my own site. In fact, it’s lingered on the backburner for so long that the concept of having my own corner of the web faded into something of an anxious shadow, following me for what feels like ages. But thanks to my incredible wife’s unwavering support, I’ve finally summoned the courage to chase down that shadow and bring my vision to life. And here it is—my website, finally up and running. It’s a small victory, but an important one. Now, with this virtual canvas at my fingertips, I suppose I better roll up my sleeves and get cracking! Here’s to new beginnings and the exciting journey ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
