<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="assets/css/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://www.brianbaldock.com/">
  <title>Brian Baldock</title>
  <subtitle>This blog will have numerous amounts of subject matter that I think about and try to master</subtitle>
  <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/" />
  
  <updated>2024-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Brian Baldock</name>
    <email>website@bdock.mozmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>H.A.I.R. - A Double-Edged Sword in Modern HR Practices</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/" />
    <updated>2024-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I navigate the job market, I’m constantly grappling with the challenge of finding a position that aligns with my skills, ideas, and ambitions. The process often feels like an SEO battle, where I have to optimize my application to outsmart an &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; system rather than connect with a company on a human level. This blog post explores the implications of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt;, particularly in managing job applications and postings, and questions whether companies that rely heavily on &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; for screening truly foster the culture they claim to value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reality-of-ai-in-hr&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-reality-of-ai-in-hr&quot;&gt;The Reality of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s job market, &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt;-driven systems are commonly used to manage the influx of job applications and to post job listings across various platforms. These systems are designed to streamline the hiring process, but they also create new challenges for job seekers. Applicants must navigate keyword-optimized job descriptions and application forms designed to satisfy an algorithm rather than a hiring manager. This can feel like an uphill battle, reminiscent of the iterative process of SEO analysis, where results are seen weeks or even months after initial efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cultural-disconnect&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-cultural-disconnect&quot;&gt;The Cultural Disconnect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; for initial screenings may suggest that a company is overly reliant on technology without fully understanding its limitations. &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; screening often depends on preconceived keyword phrases that may not accurately reflect the needs of the position or the company’s culture. This can lead to a misalignment between the job posting and the actual requirements of the role. Furthermore, it raises questions about the company’s commitment to building a genuine workplace culture. If &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; departments rely too heavily on &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt;, they risk overlooking the nuanced human elements that are crucial for cultural fit and employee satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-desensitization-of-job-listings&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-desensitization-of-job-listings&quot;&gt;The Desensitization of Job Listings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job seekers often find themselves sifting through countless job postings that lack unique or specific details about the company and the role. Many job descriptions are boilerplate, failing to convey what makes the company a desirable place to work. This generic approach can desensitize applicants, making it harder for them to connect with potential employers. It also underscores a larger issue: the lack of personalized, human touch in the hiring process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-role-of-hr-in-the-ai-era&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-role-of-hr-in-the-ai-era&quot;&gt;The Role of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; in the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; Era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; departments play a critical role in balancing the efficiencies of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; with the need for human insight. While &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; can help standardize pay scales and job titles, it cannot replace the nuanced understanding that &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; professionals bring to the table. Effective &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; requires understanding the dynamics between hiring managers, their teams, and the candidates. It involves gauging what is best for both the company and the individuals involved. As such, &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; should use &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; as a tool, not a crutch, to enhance the hiring process rather than replace the human elements that are essential for building a strong organizational culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ethical-considerations-of-ai-in-hiring&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-ethical-considerations-of-ai-in-hiring&quot;&gt;The Ethical Considerations of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in Hiring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in hiring also raises important ethical considerations. Algorithms can inadvertently perpetuate biases present in the data they are trained on, leading to discriminatory practices. If not carefully monitored, &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; systems can favor certain demographics over others, undermining diversity and inclusion efforts. Companies must ensure that their &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; tools are transparent, fair, and regularly audited to prevent biased outcomes. This requires a proactive approach from &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; departments to continuously evaluate and improve the algorithms used in their hiring processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-human-touch-why-it-matters&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-human-touch-why-it-matters&quot;&gt;The Human Touch: Why It Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the critical issues with &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; is that it allows applicants to game the system. By strategically using keywords, tags, and other meta-information, job seekers can push their applications through the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; filters without necessarily being suitable candidates. This loophole highlights the fundamental flaw in relying solely on &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; for screening: it can be easily manipulated. Therefore, it’s crucial for companies to involve human reviewers in the final stages of the hiring process. Human judgment is essential to assess the true fit between a candidate and a role, something &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; cannot fully replicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future-of-ai-in-hr-a-balanced-approach&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#the-future-of-ai-in-hr-a-balanced-approach&quot;&gt;The Future of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt;: A Balanced Approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward, the integration of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; should be approached with caution and balance. Companies can benefit from the efficiencies and insights provided by &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt;, but they must also prioritize human judgment and empathy. Training &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; professionals to work alongside &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt;, rather than being replaced by it, is crucial. This includes developing skills to interpret &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; outputs critically and to make informed decisions that align with the company’s values and culture. Additionally, involving employees in discussions about &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; implementations can help mitigate fears and build trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hair&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/hair-a-double-edged-sword-in-modern-hr-practices/#hair&quot;&gt;H.A.I.R.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; is a double-edged sword. While it offers efficiency and scalability, it also risks dehumanizing the hiring process and misaligning company culture with its stated values. As job seekers, we must navigate this landscape carefully, striving to present our best selves to both algorithms and humans. Companies, on the other hand, must ensure that their use of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; enhances rather than hinders their ability to attract and retain top talent. The future of &lt;abbr title=&quot;Human Resources&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/abbr&gt; lies in finding the right balance between technological innovation and human connection. Crucially, companies must recognize that while &lt;abbr title=&quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/abbr&gt; can aid in the hiring process, it should never replace the indispensable value of human insight and judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Opossum Symposium</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/" />
    <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;After what feels like an eternity without attending any conferences, today was a refreshing change. Thanks to Mr. &lt;a href=&quot;https://zachleat.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Zach Leatherman&lt;/a&gt; and his team, a virtual symposium for 11ty was brought to life, and I couldn’t have been happier to be a part of it. The lineup boasted familiar faces from Mastodon, whom I’ve followed for years, alongside many new names, all sharing insights into the world of web technologies. It was a joy to dive into their websites and Mastodon accounts, connecting with this vibrant community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mikeneumegen.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Mike Neumegen&lt;/a&gt; for his stellar job as MC, and a big shoutout to Diane and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://whitecoatcaptioning.com/captioning-for-conferences/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;White Coat team for providing live captions&lt;/a&gt; throughout the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;kickoff&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/#kickoff&quot;&gt;Kickoff!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zach’s opening remarks set the perfect tone for the day. His humility in acknowledging the attendees and their enthusiastic participation in the chat was heartwarming. The love for the community was palpable, and it’s all thanks to Zach and his dedicated team. I’m eagerly anticipating version 3.0 and all the exciting developments they’ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;heading-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/opossum-symposium/#speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each speaker brought a unique perspective to the table, sharing their insights and passions with authenticity. It was a refreshing experience to soak in their knowledge and emotions, with no hidden agendas or endorsements in sight. Just genuine stories and a shared enthusiasm for creativity, exploration, and the evolving landscape of design and web technologies. It left me inspired to continue my journey of creation and delve deeper into the fundamentals, guided by the spirit of curiosity and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Working Away</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/working-away/" />
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/working-away/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on my career journey thus far, I find myself chipping away at summarizing the noteworthy projects I’ve undertaken. It’s been a humbling exercise, delving into memories of the various milestones and discoveries along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having built numerous websites throughout my career, ranging from brochure-style sites to intricate portals, I’ve found immense satisfaction in the process. However, the real excitement comes when I get the opportunity to work on web applications. This allows me to delve deeper into backend technologies, gaining a comprehensive understanding of the layers of security, engineering, and design that operate behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each project has been a learning experience, allowing me to expand my skill set and refine my craft. From navigating the intricacies of frontend development to mastering the complexities of backend systems, I’ve embraced every challenge with enthusiasm and determination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to evolve in my career, I’m grateful for the opportunity to contribute to meaningful projects and make a tangible impact in the digital landscape. With each new endeavor, I look forward to further growth, exploration, and discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Site</title>
    <link href="https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/new-site/" />
    <updated>2024-03-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://www.brianbaldock.com/blog/new-site/</id>
    <content xml:lang="" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been awhile since I dedicated time to working on my own site. In fact, it’s lingered on the backburner for so long that the concept of having my own corner of the web faded into something of an anxious shadow, following me for what feels like ages. But thanks to my incredible wife’s unwavering support, I’ve finally summoned the courage to chase down that shadow and bring my vision to life. And here it is—my website, finally up and running. It’s a small victory, but an important one. Now, with this virtual canvas at my fingertips, I suppose I better roll up my sleeves and get cracking! Here’s to new beginnings and the exciting journey ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
